LOUIS FERNANDEZ

M: 0405 859 846 E: louis97fernandez@gmail.com

Career Objective

I am a third year mechanical and mechatronic student searching for a new position where I can gain valuable industrial experience. I hope that this position would also help me further develop my soft skills, such as communication and teamworking skills. Most importantly, I want a position where I can continue to grow by learning how to use different engineering software, solidifying on what I already know and put into action what I have learned at university.

Educational Qualifications

Bachelor of Engineering (Honours) (Mechanical and Mechatronic Engineering)

University of Technology Sydney (UTS)

March 2016 – March 2021 (expected)

- Dean's recipient for 2016/17 /18/19
- WAM 87.92
- GPA 6.66 (7-point GPA)

Diploma in Language (Mandarin)

University of Technology Sydney (UTS)

March 2017 - Feb 2019

- Chinese Language and Culture 1, 69%
- Chinese Language and Culture 2, 76%
- Chinese Language and Culture 3, 76%
- Chinese Language and Culture 4, 66%

NSW High School Certificate

John Therry Catholic High School ATAR of 87.7

Jan 2010 – Sept 2015

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Team member

Nandos Oct 2019 – Present

- Served customers in a dynamic and fast paced environment, which helped me improve my communication skills
- Developed organisation skills and initiative by ensuring that the store was clean, and stocked for busy periods
- Able to work well under pressure as most my shifts are during the store's peak hour

Engineering Intern - Technical

Kraftech Nov 2019 – July 2020

- Create standard administrative documents such as operations and maintenance manuals, site layouts and guotes for clients
- Used Fanuc's Roboguide simulator to simulate robotic systems
- Assisted in negotiating prices with suppliers to reduce cost of parts
- Used Solidworks to produce technical drawings for manufacture and CAD models to be used in simulations

FERNANDEZ Page 1 of 6

Intern engineer

Air Conditioning Mechanical Engineers Pty Ltd (ACME)

Feb 2019 – Aug 2019

- Liaised and coordinated with clients, sub-contractors, suppliers and other stakeholders
- Prepared management reports and plans
- Followed up incomplete work or works not done at a certain quality and developed action plans to ensure these issues are rectified in a timely manner
- Identified and recommended new processes where needed for quality improvement, cost reduction and on-time delivery
- Placed orders and kept record of the materials on hand
- Assisted in planning and scheduling of mechanical activities ensuring programs are delivered on time as per the project schedule

Grocery team member

Coles

Feb 2017 – Feb 2019

- Provided excellent customer service by professionally serving each customer to assist them in locating a product and fulfilling their requests
- Worked in a team to meet certain KPIs in the most efficient and effective manner
- Maintained and replenished stock by placing each item from the roll cages onto the correct spot on the shelves or placing stock onto the correct roll cage from the pallets
- Operated manual pallet moving equipment to keep the back area safe and tidy
- Organised and displayed merchandise to drive sales of latest items

UTS Peer Assisted Study Session (U:PASS) Senior Leader University of Technology Sydney (UTS)

March 2017 - Feb 2019

- Improved upon my communication skills by finding unique ways to explain concepts to each student in a way they would understand as not all students learn the same way
- Developed efficient time management and multi-tasking skills through managing a class to ensure students understand key concepts within the time-frame given
- Developed creative thinking skills by creating worksheets and thinking of different ways to ensure each student in the session contributes something to the class
- Practised leadership skills by assisting and mentoring new leaders on how to efficiently run a UPASS session

Data Arena Demonstrator

University of Technology Sydney (UTS)

Dec 2017 – Feb 2019

- Provided viewings for internal visitors, such as students and academics, and external visitors, ranging from government officials, banks and the public
- Demonstrated the capabilities of the data arena by effectively communicating the ideas and purpose behind multiple data sets

FERNANDEZ Page 2 of 6

CORE SKILLS

- Written and verbal communication skills: I assisted in supervising ACME's sub-contractors
 where I communicated with them on a day to day basis on what works needed to be done.
 This also involved communicating and coordinating with other trades to ensure that our works
 do not interfere with theirs. I was also responsible for creating documents that was submitted
 to ACME's clients and other stakeholders.
- <u>Team player:</u> My work at Coles and Nandos helped develop my ability to work in a team as I help others with their tasks while ensuring my task is completed in a timely manner
- Organisational skills: I am able to develop work schedules by converting my objectives into achievable tasks. This was an important skill that I continually used while being employed at ACME as I was continually given multiple tasks that had tight deadlines.
- Good attention to detail: I assisted in inspecting the works completed by ACME's sub-contractors, ensuring the works comply with requirements and established standards.
- <u>Willingness to learn:</u> I am aware of my basic knowledge in the softwares and engineering fundamentals I have included below, as well as my lack of theory and experience in the industry. However, I am willing to expand on these knowledge, skills and experiences wherever possible.

Technical skills

<u>Software:</u> Solidworks (competent proficiency), MATLAB (competent proficiency), Python (basic proficiency), C and embedded C (basic proficiency)

<u>Engineering fundamentals (basic proficiency):</u> Mathematics/statistics, electronic circuits/microcontrollers, analysis and design of mechanisms, analysis and design of mechanisms systems, statics/dynamics

EXTRA CIRRICULAR ACTIVITIES

Treasurer of Biomedical Engineering Society UTS (BESUTS)

UTS Feb 2020 – Present

• Part of the executive team responsible for organising events for the society

Protospace Hackathon

UTS

July 2020 – July 2020

- Participated in workshops to gain knowledge on the different 3D printing capabilities at UTS
 Protospace
- Part of a team who developed a solution for a specific problem of remote aid
- Used Solidworks to create a working prototype for 3D printing
- Brainstormed for solutions to specific problems and continually improved on the design to ensure a working prototype was printed on time to create a video pitch

FERNANDEZ Page 3 of 6

Students Helping Students

UTS

August 2017 – August 2017

- Developed my communication skills by clearly answering certain inquiries that new students have during the first two weeks of the semester
- For further details refer to the Letter of Reference below.

Peer Network

UTS

Dec 2016 – August 2017

- Developed skills such as cross-cultural, leadership and communication skills by attending two mandatory training sessions. The training session also taught us how to deal with harassment and discrimination
- Involved communicating with new students by answering any inquiries they had about commencing university or redirecting them to the correct department for help
- Developed team working skills by working with fellow peers to finish each task in a timely manner

FERNANDEZ Page 4 of 6

Academic Transcript

Year	Session	Subject No.	Title	Ver	Mark	Grade	Credit Points
2020	Spring Session	41013	Robotics	1	91	High Distinction	6.0
2020	Spring Session	41045	Engineering Practice Preparation 2	2	82	Distinction	3.0
2020	Spring Session	48270	Entrepreneurship and Commercialisation	7	69	Credit	6.0
2020	Spring Session	48650	Mechanical Design 2	4	93	High Distinction	6.0
2020	Autumn Session	48260	Engineering Project Management	6	89	High Distinction	6.0
2020	Autumn Session	48531	Electromechanical Automation	5	97	High Distinction	6.0
2020	Autumn Session	48641	Fluid Mechanics	3	95	High Distinction	6.0
2019	Spring Session	41014	Sensors and Control for Mechatronic Systems	1	87	High Distinction	6.0
2019	Spring Session	41038	Engineering Practice Reflection 1	1	84	Distinction	3.0
2019	Spring Session	48250	Engineering Economics and Finance	4	90	High Distinction	6.0
2019	Spring Session	48651	Thermodynamics	5	97	High Distinction	6.0
2019	Autumn Session	41036	Engineering Professional Experience 1	1	91	High Distinction	6.0
2019	Autumn Session	41037	Work Integrated Learning 1	1	91	High Distinction	12.0
2018	Spring Session	48623	Mechatronics 2	1	86	High Distinction	6.0
2018	Spring Session	48660	Dynamics and Control	3	90	High Distinction	6.0
2018	Autumn Session	48600	Mechanical Design 1	1	85	High Distinction	6.0
2018	Autumn Session	48642	Strength of Engineering Materials	3	81	Distinction	6.0
2017	Spring Session	48240	Design and Innovation Fundamentals	5	87	High Distinction	6.0
2017	Spring Session	48622	Mechatronics 1	1	89	High Distinction	6.0
2017	Autumn Session	48331	Mechanics of Solids	3	98	High Distinction	6.0
2017	Autumn Session	48640	Machine Dynamics	3	70	Credit	6.0
2016	Summer Session	41035	Engineering Practice Preparation 1	1	70	Credit	3.0
2016	Spring Session	33230	Mathematical Modelling 2	4	89	High Distinction	6.0
2016	Spring Session	48510	Introduction to Electrical Engineering	3	94	High Distinction	6.0
2016	Spring Session	48620	Fundamentals of Mechanical Engineering	3	94	High Distinction	6.0
2016	Spring Session	48621	Manufacturing Engineering	3	81	Distinction	6.0
2016	Autumn Session	33130	Mathematical Modelling 1	4	94	High Distinction	6.0
2016	Autumn Session	48230	Engineering Communication	5	77	Distinction	6.0
2016	Autumn Session	48610	Introduction to Mechanical and Mechatronic Engineering	3	91	High Distinction	6.0
2016	Autumn Session	68037	Physical Modelling	3	75	Distinction	6.0

Referees are available upon request

FERNANDEZ Page 5 of 6



To Whom It May Concern,

RE: Letter of Reference for Louis Fernandez,

Volunteer with the UTS Students Helping Students Project

I am writing to highlight the valuable contribution that Louis Fernandez made to the University of Technology Sydney (UTS) *Students Helping Students* project as a volunteer during the Spring 2017 session. Through the project, experienced student volunteers such as Louis assisted new students and visitors during the first weeks of the session – helping to field a broad range of queries, including assisting people to familiarise themselves with the campus and helping with general enrolment questions.

During the Spring 2017 session, student volunteers assisted with over 3000 enquiries, including queries that involved walking a student or visitor to a location on campus. Furthermore, the data and feedback that volunteers collected has helped to inform various efforts at UTS aimed at improving the first-year experience and supporting student retention and success. In addition to this role, Louis acted as a volunteer team leader, which involved monitoring and motivating their team, reporting any incidents to security and acting as a key contact person for UTS staff members.

Louis was recommended to participate in this project by the UTS *Peer Network* – a project which selects and trains experienced students to assist new students in adjusting to university life. Louis volunteered 12 hours to the Students Helping Students project this term, in addition to completing a training session related to proactive customer service approaches.

Volunteering with the *Students Helping Students* project entails learning and utilising new skills, sharing complex information effectively with others, managing multiple demands, engaging proactively with the public, being punctual and considerate, recording important data and supporting teammates with their work. We are very pleased with how Louis performed as a volunteer with the Students Helping Students project and would welcome future involvement with this project. I can recommend Louis for any opportunity that might require similar skills and wish Louis much success in the future.

Kind regards,

Brett Smout Director

Student Services Unit

University of Technology Sydney

FERNANDEZ Page 6 of 6